worldwatch.org 2008-06-23

# Privacy Policy | Worldwatch Institute

If you are just browsing the Worldwatch Institute website (www.worldwatch.org), rest assured that no personal information regarding your use of the site will be collected by Worldwatch. However, if you register to receive e-mail updates from us, download a free PDF, purchase a publication online, or make a donation online, you will be asked for personal information such as your name, address, and e-mail address. 

Certain information about the User, such as IP addresses, navigation through the site, software used, time spent, and other similar information may be stored on the Worldwatch Institute servers. It may also be written to the User's computer system in small data pieces known as "cookies." These cookies will not specifically identify the User. 

Information collected will be used internally only for website traffic analysis. If the User specifically provides unique identifying information, such as name, address, and other information on forms stored on this site, such information will be used to fulfill orders and for statistical purposes and will not be published for general access. The Worldwatch Institute, however, assumes no responsibility for the security of information entered by the User on our site. 

While the Worldwatch Institute does record your IP address (the Internet address of your computer) and other information such as your browser type and operating system, this information is used only to help us learn about the geographical distribution of our website visitors and the technology they use to access our site. This information is never connected with the personal information you supply to us if you register on our website. 

Registering on our site is optional. If you choose not to register or to provide personal information, you can still use the Worldwatch Institute website. You will not, however, be able to receive e-mail updates through the site, download free PDFs of our materials, order a publication online, or make a donation online. 

The Worldwatch Institute employs a range of technologies to protect the information maintained on our systems from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.
